Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine and today we have a great elementary level lesson all about
我是Catherine，今天我们有一节很棒的基础课程，主题是关于
having fun.
玩得开心。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are going to have a lot of fun and well before we explain what exactly we're
今天我们会玩得很开心，在我们解释具体要做什么之前，
going to do, why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview.
不如先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, so the word we're previewing today is a noun.
好的，我们今天预览的词是一个名词。
It's a thing.
它是一个东西。
It's a roller coaster.
它是过山车。
Alright a roller coaster.
好的，过山车。
So that's what we're going to do today.
这就是我们今天要做的。
We're going to get on a roller coaster.
我们要去坐过山车。
But what is a roller coaster?
但什么是过山车呢？
Well a roller coaster is something that we see often times in parks, amusement parks.
嗯，过山车是我们经常在公园、游乐园里看到的东西。
And it's like a little train but it can go upside down and it goes very fast and it turns
它像一列小火车，但可以倒着开，速度很快，还会转弯，
and it's supposed to make you scared and happy.
目的是让你既害怕又开心。
Okay.
好的。
So it goes very fast and yeah many people have probably seen it.
所以它速度很快，嗯，很多人可能都见过。
It goes very fast and as you say up and down and well you just get on it because it's fun.
它速度很快，就像你说的，上上下下，你坐上去就是因为好玩。
You go fast and you get scared because you're going so fast and sometimes you're going upside
你开得很快，因为速度太快你会害怕，有时还会倒着开。
down.
倒着开。
Exactly and for some reason, I don't know why, but in many romance languages the name
没错，而且不知为什么，在很多罗曼语系的语言里，它的名字
is Russian mountains.
是“俄罗斯山”。
Exactly, yeah.
确实，是的。
It's also in Spanish it's also a Russian mountain.
在西班牙语里也是“俄罗斯山”。
Yeah.
是的。
Montaña rusa.
Montaña rusa。
So I think the reason is because back in the day, back you know a hundred years ago when
所以我觉得原因是因为以前，你知道一百年前，
they were starting, the first roller coasters came from Russia.
当它们刚开始出现时，第一批过山车来自俄罗斯。
Oh wow.
哦，哇。
Yeah.
是的。
So that's why it's called like that.
所以它才被这么叫。
Well that's a theory.
嗯，那是个理论。
I'm not sure but take a listen to today's dialogue.
我不确定，但请听今天的对话。
We'll hear it one time and when we come back we'll be talking about more interesting and
我们会听一遍，回来后再讨论更多关于过山车的
exciting phrases and words about roller coasters.
有趣和刺激的短语和词汇。
I'm so excited!
我太兴奋了！
We're finally here!
我们终于到了！
Six Flags Magic Mountain.
六旗魔术山。
This is the best amusement park in the world.
这是世界上最好的游乐园。
All right settle down now.
好了，冷静点。
You're going to give yourself a heart attack.
你会把自己弄出心脏病的。
I can't believe they charge us $35 each.
真不敢相信他们每人收我们35美元。
Seems like such a rip-off don't you think?
感觉像是敲竹杠，你不觉得吗？
It's not like I'm going to get on these things.
我又不是要坐这些东西。
Whoa Viper!
哇，毒蛇！
That's the world's highest and fastest roller coaster!
那是世界上最高最快的过山车！
You go at more than 100 miles per hour.
速度超过每小时100英里。
I want to go on that one.
我想坐那个。
Can I mom please?
妈妈，可以吗？求你了？
Can I?
可以吗？
Chris I'm not sure you should get on that.
克里斯，我不确定你该坐那个。
It seems a bit too much for you and we just had breakfast 30 minutes ago.
对你来说有点过了，而且我们30分钟前才吃完早餐。
I don't think it's a good idea.
我觉得这不是个好主意。
Oh come on mom.
哦，妈妈，别这样。
I can handle it.
我能应付。
I promise I won't ask for anything else.
我保证不会再要别的东西了。
Besides it's not like I'm going to throw up or anything.
再说我又不会吐或什么的。
Let him go Carol.
让他去吧，卡罗尔。
He'll be fine.
他会没事的。
All right!
好吧！
Yeah this is amazing!
耶，太棒了！
See how high up we're going?
看我们升得多高？
All right we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So uh interesting that I think this is very common.
嗯，有趣的是，我觉得这很常见。
You get on one of these things, you go so fast that you just throw up.
你坐上这种东西，速度太快就会吐。
Have you ever thrown up?
你吐过吗？
On a roller coaster?
在过山车上？
No never.
没有，从来没有。
No me neither.
没有，我也没有。
All right well maybe it's not that common but let's take a look at some of the words
好吧，也许没那么常见，但让我们看看这个男孩和他父母
that we hear in this conversation between a boy and his parents.
对话中出现的一些词汇。
All right so as we mentioned this word throw up, to throw up.
好的，就像我们提到的，这个词是“throw up”，呕吐。
Why don't we take a look at that one first although it's almost at the end of the dialogue.
不如我们先看看这个词，虽然它在对话快结尾处。
What is it to throw up?
“throw up”是什么意思？
Okay well to throw is different than to throw up.
好的，“throw”和“throw up”不同。
So remember that these two words go together to mean to vomit.
所以记住这两个词连在一起意思是呕吐。
That means that the things in your stomach come out your mouth.
就是说你胃里的东西从嘴里出来。
So like we heard in the dialogue they came in like bleh.
就像我们在对话里听到的，他们进来时“bleh”。
Yeah it's a very disgusting sound right?
是的，那声音很恶心，对吧？
And so sometimes people throw up when they eat too much, sometimes they throw up when
所以有时人们吃太多会吐，有时生病会吐，
they're sick, and sometimes they throw up after riding a roller coaster.
有时坐完过山车会吐。
And so this is an important phrase to know.
所以这是一个需要知道的重要短语。
Or like when you're on a boat you get seasick and you throw up.
或者像在船上晕船会吐。
Or in a car sometimes you get carsick.
或者在车里有时会晕车。
All right so as we mentioned we're also visiting an amusement park.
好的，就像我们提到的，我们也在参观一个游乐园。
So why don't we explain this word a little bit, amusement park.
所以我们来稍微解释一下这个词，“amusement park”。
Okay first of all everyone probably knows the word park.
好的，首先大家可能都知道“park”这个词。
You know it's a public place.
你知道，它是一个公共场所。
But in this case an amusement park is a park of fun.
但在这里，“amusement park”是一个充满乐趣的公园。
Amusement means fun.
“Amusement”意思是乐趣。
And so it's usually a place that you go to and you pay a price and they give you a ticket
所以它通常是一个你去的地方，付钱后他们会给你一张票，
and you can play all day long.
你可以玩一整天。
So they have roller coasters and food and shows.
所以那里有过山车、食物和表演。
And probably the most famous or well known amusement park is Disneyland.
可能最著名或最知名的游乐园是迪士尼乐园。
So that's an amusement park.
所以那就是一个游乐园。
Exactly and there's lots of fun things to do for people of all ages.
没错，那里有很多有趣的事情可以做，适合所有年龄段的人。
All right and now the kid was so excited that the mom said all right you're gonna give yourself
好的，现在那个孩子太兴奋了，妈妈就说：“好了，你会把自己弄出心脏病的。”
a heart attack.
心脏病发作。
Okay well a heart attack is another serious health issue.
好的，“heart attack”是另一个严重的健康问题。
We talked about throwing up before.
我们之前谈过呕吐。
Is when your heart stops beating.
就是你的心脏停止跳动。
So maybe something is stuck or there's some problem with your heart and there's no more
所以可能有什么东西堵住了，或者你的心脏有问题，
blood going through your heart.
没有血液流过心脏。
And so it's a very very serious issue.
所以这是一个非常非常严重的问题。
But in this case she's saying you're so excited you might hurt your heart.
但在这里，她说你太兴奋了，可能会伤到心脏。
You're gonna have a heart attack.
你会心脏病发作。
You might hurt yourself because you're so excited.
你可能会因为太兴奋而伤到自己。
Right so she's exaggerating.
对，所以她是在夸张。
That's not really going to happen but she's trying to warn him.
那不会真的发生，但她是在警告他。
All right and now the father mentioned that they paid $35 for each of their tickets and
好的，现在父亲提到他们每张票付了35美元，
he thought it was a ripoff.
他觉得这是敲竹杠。
Okay ripoff is a great great phrase that we use in spoken English to describe something
好的，“ripoff”是一个很棒的口语短语，用来描述
that's unfair.
不公平的事情。
So a price that's unfair.
所以是不公平的价格。
Okay so you can maybe go to the market right and you ask how much a sweater is and they'll
好的，比如你去市场，问一件毛衣多少钱，
tell you it's $100.
他们告诉你100美元。
You think that's a ripoff.
你觉得那是敲竹杠。
What a ripoff!
真是宰人啊！
I can buy a sweater for $20.
我花20美元就能买一件毛衣。
So a hundred is definitely a ripoff.
所以一百美元绝对是宰人。
All right so that's a ripoff.
好吧，那真是宰人。
It was a ripoff.
那真是宰人。
He's not very happy with how much money he paid.
他对自己付了那么多钱很不高兴。
Not at all.
一点也不。
All right and now the kid was talking about the roller coaster that is the highest and
好了，现在那个孩子在谈论最高最快的过山车，他说速度超过每小时一百英里。
fastest roller coaster and he said that the speed was at more than a hundred miles per
最快过山车，他说速度超过每小时一百英里。
hour.
每小时。
So what about this miles per hour?
那这个“每小时英里”是怎么回事？
Okay this is very important if you go to America you'll see that the speeds on the road are
好的，这非常重要，如果你去美国，你会看到路上的速度标志都是英里每小时。
all in miles per hour.
都是英里每小时。
So mile is a distance.
所以英里是一个距离单位。
And per hour means how many miles you can travel every hour.
而“每小时”意味着你每小时能走多少英里。
So in one hour you can go a hundred miles.
所以在一小时内你能走一百英里。
So we have the equivalent right?
所以我们有对应的单位，对吧？
We have like kilometers per hour.
我们有像公里每小时这样的单位。
Exactly and so miles per hour, kilometers per hour, these are both called speeds.
没错，英里每小时、公里每小时，这些都叫速度。
And well this is called the imperial system right?
嗯，这叫做英制单位，对吧？
You use miles, you use inches and feet whereas the kilometers or centimeters or meters you
你们用英里、英寸和英尺，而公里、厘米或米则是公制单位，对吧？
would use the metric system right?
你们会用公制单位，对吧？
Exactly because the counting is done by meters.
没错，因为计量是以米为基础的。
Meters metric.
米制，公制。
So in this case we're in America we know that because the speed limit is a hundred miles
所以在这个例子中，我们在美国，因为我们知道限速是一百英里，或者这里的速度是一百英里每小时。
or the speed here is a hundred miles an hour.
或者这里的速度是一百英里每小时。
We know that we're in America because the speed the boy is talking about is miles per
我们知道我们在美国，因为那个男孩说的速度是英里每小时。
hour.
每小时。
Very good and I think yeah use it in North America and that's pretty much it right?
很好，我想是的，在北美使用，差不多就这样，对吧？
I think they use miles in Britain.
我想英国也用英里。
Really?
真的吗？
I'm positive I'd have to check with my British friends.
我确定，我得跟我的英国朋友确认一下。
Alright okay so that's all the words we have for language takeaway.
好了，这就是我们语言点部分的所有单词。
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to explain some phrases.
让我们再听一遍对话，然后回来解释一些短语。
I'm so excited!
我太兴奋了！
We're finally here!
我们终于到了！
Six Flags Magic Mountain.
六旗魔术山。
This is the best amusement park in the world!
这是世界上最好的游乐园！
Alright settle down now.
好了，安静下来。
You're gonna give yourself a heart attack.
你会把自己弄出心脏病的。
I can't believe they charge us $35 each.
我真不敢相信他们每人收我们35美元。
It seems like such a ripoff don't you think?
这简直是宰人，你不觉得吗？
It's not like I'm gonna get on these things.
我又不打算坐这些东西。
Whoa Viper that's the world's highest and fastest roller coaster!
哇，Viper，那是世界上最高最快的过山车！
You go at more than 100 miles per hour.
你以超过每小时100英里的速度前进。
I want to go on that one.
我想坐那个。
Can I mom please?
妈妈，我能坐吗？求你了？
Can I?
我能吗？
Chris I'm not sure you should get on that.
克里斯，我不确定你应该坐那个。
It seems a bit too much for you and we've just had breakfast 30 minutes ago.
对你来说可能有点过了，而且我们30分钟前才吃完早餐。
I don't think it's a good idea.
我觉得这不是个好主意。
Come on mom.
拜托了，妈妈。
I can handle it.
我能应付。
I promise I won't ask for anything else.
我保证我不会再要别的东西了。
Besides it's not like I'm gonna throw up or anything.
再说，我又不会吐什么的。
Let him go Carol.
让他去吧，卡罗尔。
He'll be fine.
他会没事的。
Alright!
好吧！
Yeah!
耶！
This is amazing!
太棒了！
See how high up we're going?
看我们升得多高？
Whoa!
哇！
Alright we're back so now why don't we start with three phrases that we have prepared for
好了，我们回来了，现在为什么不从我们为你们准备的三个短语开始呢，在流利度构建部分。
you today in Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Fluency Builder.
Okay this first phrase Marco is definitely a parent phrase.
好的，第一个短语马可，这绝对是一个家长用语。
Okay so this is something that you often hear parents saying to their children.
好的，这是你经常听到父母对孩子说的话。
They say settle down now.
他们说“安静下来”。
Settle down now.
“安静下来”。
Teachers say this too.
老师也这么说。
Yeah.
是的。
Alright everyone settle down.
好了，大家安静下来。
That means if I'm really excited and I want to talk and I'm running around the room and
这意味着如果我非常兴奋，想说话，在房间里跑来跑去，我的老师说“安静下来”，那就是说安静点，慢下来，坐下，别说话。
my teacher says settle down now that means quiet down, go slowly, sit down, don't talk.
安静点，慢下来，坐下，别说话。
It means calm down.
意思是冷静下来。
Calm down yeah.
冷静下来，是的。
So to calm down to relax.
所以是冷静下来，放松。
Exactly.
没错。
Settle down.
安静下来。
Alright and now the next phrase is a very kids phrase I think right?
好了，下一个短语是一个非常孩子气的短语，对吧？
That you would use on your parents.
你会对父母用的那种。
So if they say no you can't go to your friend's house.
所以如果他们说不行，你不能去朋友家。
Oh come on please.
哦，拜托了。
Oh mom come on.
哦，妈妈，拜托了。
Alright so what do you mean with that phrase?
好的，那这个短语是什么意思？
Come on come on what?
“拜托”什么？
So in this we have a child who's asking something.
所以在这里，有一个孩子在请求什么。
He's saying can you please let me do something.
他在说你能让我做某事吗？
Please come on.
拜托了。
That means I'm encouraging you to change your mind or to let me do something.
这意味着我在鼓励你改变主意，或者让我做某事。
So please let me have my way.
所以请让我如愿以偿。
Right right.
对，对。
Alright so come on and you don't only use it as a child or with your parents right?
好的，所以“拜托”不仅限于孩子对父母用，对吧？
You can encourage your friends to like come on come with me to the bar.
你也可以鼓励朋友，比如“来吧，跟我去酒吧”。
Come on.
“来吧”。
Come on let's go.
“来吧，我们走”。
Please.
“求你了”。
Come on.
“来吧”。
Alright.
“好吧”。
Very good.
很好。
You know you want to.
你知道你想的。
And our last phrase I can handle it.
我们最后一个短语是“我能应付”。
Okay this is next to the phrase oh come on.
好的，这跟在“哦，拜托”这个短语后面。
So the boy is trying to explain that he's big enough and old enough to go on a roller
所以那个男孩在试图解释他足够大、足够老，可以坐过山车，但他妈妈不知道。
coaster but his mother doesn't know.
可以坐过山车，但他妈妈不知道。
She says oh I don't know.
她说“哦，我不知道”。
You know you're too young.
你知道你太小了。
And so he says I can handle it.
所以他说“我能应付”。
That means I am big enough and old enough to go on a roller coaster.
这意味着我足够大、足够老，可以坐过山车。
I won't have a problem.
我不会有问题。
So you can do it right.
所以你能做到，对吧。
Basically I am good enough to do it.
基本上我足够好，能做到。
So for example if I give you a very hard project you can say I can handle it.
所以例如，如果我给你一个非常难的项目，你可以说“我能应付”。
I can do it.
“我能做到”。
You could also say I am very busy right now.
你也可以说“我现在很忙”。
I can't handle it.
“我应付不了”。
Okay.
“好的”。
I can't.
“我不能”。
I can't do it.
“我做不到”。
I'm sorry.
“对不起”。
I can't do it.
我做不到。
Alright.
好吧。
Very good.
非常好。
Interesting phrases there.
那里有些有趣的短语。
They're very useful and very very common in spoken English in North America and well
它们非常有用，而且在北美以及很多地方的英语口语中非常非常常见。
a lot of places.
很多地方。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue for the third time and we'll be back.
那我们不如再听一遍对话，然后回来。
I'm so excited.
我太兴奋了。
We're finally here.
我们终于到了。
Six Flags Magic Mountain.
六旗魔术山。
This is the best amusement park in the world.
这是世界上最好的游乐园。
All right.
好了。
Settle down now.
冷静下来。
You're going to give yourself a heart attack.
你会把自己吓出心脏病的。
I can't believe I'm here.
我真不敢相信我在这里。
I'm so excited.
我太兴奋了。
I can't believe they charge us $35 each.
我真不敢相信他们每人收我们35美元。
Seems like such a ripoff, don't you think?
感觉像是敲诈，你不觉得吗？
It's not like I'm going to get on these things.
我又不打算坐这些玩意儿。
Whoa.
哇。
Viper.
毒蛇。
That's the world's highest and fastest roller coaster.
那是世界上最高最快的过山车。
You go at more than 100 miles per hour.
时速超过100英里。
I want to go on that one.
我想坐那个。
Can I, mom, please?
妈妈，我能坐吗？求你了？
Can I?
我能吗？
Chris, I'm not sure you should get on that.
克里斯，我不确定你该坐那个。
It seems a bit too much for you and we just had breakfast 30 minutes ago.
对你来说似乎有点太刺激了，而且我们30分钟前才吃过早餐。
I don't think it's a good idea.
我觉得这不是个好主意。
Come on, mom.
拜托，妈妈。
I can handle it.
我能应付。
I promise I won't ask for anything else.
我保证不会再要别的了。
Besides, it's not like I'm going to throw up or anything.
再说，我又不会吐或什么的。
Let him go, Kel.
让他去吧，凯尔。
He'll be fine.
他会没事的。
All right.
好吧。
Yeah, this is amazing.
是啊，这太棒了。
See how high up we're going?
看到我们升得多高了吗？
Whoa.
哇。
All right.
好了。
So this amusement park, Magic Mountain, it actually is a little bit bigger than I thought.
所以这个游乐园，魔法山，实际上比我想象的要大一点。
All right, so this amusement park, Magic Mountain, it actually exists in the United States, right?
好了，所以这个游乐园，魔法山，它确实在美国存在，对吧？
It does.
是的。
And Six Flags is really a brand, so there are many different amusement parks called
而六旗其实是一个品牌，所以有很多不同的游乐园都叫
Six Flags and each one has a different name.
六旗，每个都有不同的名字。
I'm not sure where Magic Mountain is, but-
我不确定魔法山在哪里，但是——
That one's in California.
那个在加州。
Yeah.
是的。
Then you have Six Flags Greater America or something like that.
然后还有六旗大美国之类的。
Yeah, that's my Chicago Six Flags.
对，那是我芝加哥的六旗。
That's the one in Chicago?
那是芝加哥的那个吗？
Yeah.
是的。
So they're basically amusement parks and they're famous because they have really great or intense
所以它们基本上都是游乐园，而且它们出名是因为有非常棒或刺激的
roller coasters, right?
过山车，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So the one that we heard about in today's dialogue is called Viper, like the snake,
所以我们在今天对话里听到的那个叫毒蛇，就像蛇一样，
and that one is at the amusement park in California you mentioned.
而且那个在你提到的加州游乐园里。
But the famous ride in Chicago is Batman the Ride.
但芝加哥著名的游乐设施是蝙蝠侠之旅。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Because you sit on a seat, but there's no place for your feet, so your feet swing in
因为你坐在座位上，但没有放脚的地方，所以你的脚在风中
the wind.
晃荡。
And it's very fast and you don't actually sit on a train, right?
而且它非常快，你实际上不是坐在火车上，对吧？
The track is on top of your head.
轨道在你头顶上。
Exactly.
没错。
And you're hanging like a bat.
你像蝙蝠一样吊着。
So you see everyone downstairs.
所以你能看到楼下所有人。
Yeah.
是的。
Well, not downstairs, down at the bottom.
嗯，不是楼下，是下面。
And I hear they have a very serious problem with people losing their shoes.
我听说他们有个很严重的问题，就是人们会掉鞋子。
I heard about this.
我听说过这个。
Yeah, so-
是啊，所以——
People wearing sandals and they just fly off.
人们穿着凉鞋，它们就直接飞出去了。
Exactly.
没错。
So I want to warn everyone, if you go to Chicago or you go to these upside down, these flipped
所以我想提醒大家，如果你去芝加哥或者去这些倒挂的、翻转的
roller coasters, you should bring real shoes, not sandals.
过山车，你应该穿真正的鞋子，而不是凉鞋。
All right.
好了。
Well, as we mentioned, in many languages, in the Romance languages, they're called Russian
嗯，正如我们提到的，在很多语言中，尤其是在罗曼语族里，它们被称为“俄罗斯山”。
Mountains.
山。
I wonder, for our Russian listeners, do you have any intense or great roller coasters
我想知道，对于我们的俄罗斯听众来说，你们在俄罗斯有没有什么刺激或超棒的过山车？
in Russia?
在俄罗斯？
I mean, if they come from Russia, they should have amazing roller coasters there, right?
我的意思是，如果它们来自俄罗斯，那儿的过山车应该很厉害，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Or do you have any idea why we call them Russian Mountains in other languages?
或者你们知道为什么在其他语言里我们叫它们“俄罗斯山”吗？
Please let us know.
请告诉我们。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We also welcome your questions and comments on other issues.
我们也欢迎你们对其他问题的提问和评论。
So until next time, everyone.
那么，下次再见，各位。
Bye.
再见。
Let's get back to business.
我们回到正事吧。